Guide to the Federal Theatre Project photograph collection, 1936-1939
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
- Series 4: Microfiche, 1936-1939; (10 boxes)
  - How Long Brethren? 445, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Svo Soren, dancer, portrait (Steiner)".
  - How Long Brethren? 545, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Dance project Christ Church (Waterbury)".
  - How Long Brethren? 566, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Lawrence Gellert, music composer, portrait (Helkin)".
  - Hymn to the Rising Sun, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Chain gang Ritz Theatre (Wernli)".
  - The Idle Inn 36, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Anglo-Jewish theater".
  - Immediate Comment 965, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Dance project; studio character shots (Steiner)".
  - In Heaven and Earth 33, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Publicity shots".
  - In Heaven and Earth 34, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stage set; production shots Willias and Majestic Theatres".
  - In Heaven and Earth 77, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
  - Injunction Granted 30, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caricature".
  - Injunction Granted 37, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
  - Injunction Granted 102, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Backstage; production shots; entrance; stage set Biltmore Theatre (Helkin)".
  - Injunction Granted 105, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Vito Marcantonio, Congressman Biltmore Theatre".
  - Injunction Granted 111, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
  - Injunction Granted 128, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Norman Lloyd".
  - Injunction Granted 135, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Backstage; entrance Biltmore Theatre".
  - Injunction Granted 156, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Cartoon".
  - Injunction Granted 163, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Lantern slides".
  - Introducing Mr. Punch 640, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Puppeteers, portrait (Waterbury)".
  - Introducing Mr. Punch 644, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots; audience Van Guard Community Center (Helkin)".
  - Iolanthe 277, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Costume. production portraits Daly's Theatre (Monoson, Stiener)".
  - Iolanthe 440, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan, audience Silver Lake, Staten Island (Waterbury)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 184, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Principals of cast Adelphi Theatre (Haber)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 186, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stage and production shot; Yiddish (Waterbury, Wernli)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 186A, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Yiddish, portraits (Waterbury)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 186C, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots; Yiddish unit (Waterbury)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 189, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stage Scenes (Helkin)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 192, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Suitcase unit (Wernli)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 202, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Buzz Windrip, portrait; Yiddish unit (Horn)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 203, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Suitcase unit; portrait 1f leads (Black.)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 204, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Brooklyn and Queen's unit Majestic Theatre (Waterbury)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 207, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "New Bishop George Probert, portrait Adelphi Theatre (Haber)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 212, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "New Bishop George Probert, portrait, Adelphi Theatre (Haber)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 214, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Yiddish unit, portrait (Black)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 219, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Suitcase unit; stage sets (Helkin)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 220, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Opening night celebrities Adelphi Theatre (Haber)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 227, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Suitcase unit Majestic Theatre (Helkin)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 236, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots; stage sets Adelphi Theatre (Wernli)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 236A, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots; stage sets Adelphi Theatre (Waterbury)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 241, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots Adelphi Theatre (Helkin)".
  - It Can't Happen Here 405, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan Staten Island (Wernli)"
  - It Can't Happen Here 408, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan, audience Owl's Head Park".
  - It Can't Happen Here No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots-color positive".
  - It Happened on Christmas Eve 256, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 99)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Bruce Library".
  - Jack and the Beanstalk 484, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan Washington Square Park (Wernli)".
  - Jack and the Beanstalk 492, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan Kelly field (Helkin)".
  - Jack and the Beanstalk 522, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan 35th Street workshop".
  - The Jew who Knew Washington 298, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama (Wernli)".
  - Jewish Pageant 393, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Madison Square Garden (Waterbury)".
  - Joan of Arc 379, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community Drama (Waterbury)"
  - Johnny Johnson 739, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shot (Nielsen)".
  - Just Ten Days 482, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
  - Katcha and the Devil 254, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Marionette workshop (Waterbury)".
  - Kinch, Myra No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
  - Kondolf, George 593, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Studio portrait (Steiner)".
  - Kondof, George 674, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Board meeting (Wernli)".
  - Kramm, Joseph No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
  - Ladies' Aid Strike 517, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Central Methodist Church (Helkin)".
  - Ladies and Hussars 537, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Hebrew Educational Society (Helkin)".
  - Lady White and Lady Yellow 497, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama St. Mark's Church (Arnold)".
  - Lafayette Theatre 167, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    1 negative and 2 positives. The negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stagehands (Waterbury)".
  - Lafayette Theatre 196, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
  - Lafayette Theatre 206, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Prize winners (Rappaport)".
  - Lafayette Theatre 323, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Wadrobe department (Waterbury)".
  - Lafayette Theatre 454, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Personnel".
  - Lafayette Theatre 588, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Seating capacity (Helkin)".
  - LaGuardia, Fiorello 51, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Myor of New York, New York City".
  - Life and Death of an American 804, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "George Sklary, author, portrait".
  - Life and Death of an American 912, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Studio, costume portraits".
  - Life and Death of an American 946, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Cast portraits; stage sets (Helkin, Waterbury)".
  - Life and Death of an American 958, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
  - Life and Death of an American 960, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Publicity sturt (Helkin)".
  - Life and Death of an American 962, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Character portraits (Waterbury)".
  - Life and Death of an American 969, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots Maxine Elliott's Theatre (Helkin, Steiner)".
  - The Lights O' London 40, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portraits; production shots Palm Gardens".
  - The Lights O' London 106, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Audience scene".
  - Linns, Jack 348, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Stage director Adelphi Theatre (Steiner)".
  - Little Black Heliotrope 409, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama St. Augustine's Chapel (Black)".
  - Living Newspaper Unit 41, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Office".
  - Living Newspaper Unit 267, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Backstage Biltmore Theatre".
  - Living Newspaper Unit 276, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Office staff (Haber)".
  - Lloyd, Norman 151, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Barrel Story".
  - The Lonely Man 549, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Newspaper clipping (Nielsen)".
  - Love in Humble Life 304, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Studio portraits; production shots Daly's Theatre (Black, Wernli)".
  - Lunatics at Large 561, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Touchstone Drama Guild (Helkin)".
  - Lyric Theatre No #, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Inside, outside shots".
  - Macbeth 6, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Nat Carson, designer".
  - Macbeth 42, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Costume, production shots Lafayette Theatre".
  - Macbeth 43, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Opening night; audience street scenes".
  - Macbeth 114, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Painting scene".
  - Macbeth 190, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Visit of Ernst Toller".
  - Macbeth 800, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots; audience".
  - Macbeth 833, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Costume, studio portraits (Rose, Waterbury)".
  - The Machine Age 250, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Frank Williamson, portrait (Steiner)".
  - The Machine Age 352, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    Portraits of leads Majestic Theatre (Steiner)".
  - The Machine Age 359, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Portraits (Cotler)".
  - The Machine Age 377, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots Majestic Theatre (Steiner)".
  - Majestic Theatre 75, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads"Stage Set".
  - Marionettes 10, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Florida, Jacksonville".
  - Marionettes 18, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Posters".
  - Marionettes 20, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Mr. Crampton".
  - Marionettes 45, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Audience Mill Hotel".
  - Marionettes 47, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Performing; workshop".
  - Marionettes 453, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Anniversary Green wich House (Wernli)".
  - Marionettes 661, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Magical illusion, rooster (Nielsen)".
  - Marionettes No #A, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Genesis-Diagram of marionette Adam".
  - Marionettes No #B, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
  - Maxine Elliott's Theatre 634, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
  - Melodies on Parade 460, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan Silver Lake Park, Staten Island (Arnold)".
  - Melodies on Parade 553, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Copy letter (Helkin)".
  - Melodies on Parade 668, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Arts 115, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Exhibit".
  - Metropolitan Museum of Arts 120, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Madame Sikeliano".
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream 403, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan Staten Island (Wernli)".
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream 407, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Director's conference Staten Island (Waterbury)".
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream 415, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Caravan; audience, sound, lights Staten Island (Waterbury)".
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream 423, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Audience; Caravan Smithfield, Long Island (Waterbury)".
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream 425, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Production shots; Caravan Kelly Field (Waterbury)".
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream 427, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Audience; Caravan Prospect Park (Waterbury)".
  - The Mikado 52, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Washington Irving High School".
  - The Mikado 234, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Church of the Good Shepard (Wernli)".
  - The Mikado 246, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Community drama Hebrew Orphen Asylum (Waterbury)".
  - The Mikado 647, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Vera Meyers, portrait (Steiner)".
  - The Mikado 649, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "1,000,000 ticket (Nielsen)".
  - The Mikado 654, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Miss Rubinstein, portrait (Rose)".
  - The Mikado 665, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "1,000,000 ticket winner (Helkin)".
  - The Mikado 676, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Opening night celebrities Academy of Music (Helkin)".
  - The Mikado 682, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Academy of Music (Wernli)".
  - The Mikado 715, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
    2 negatives and 2 positives. One negative and one positive have writing on their envelopes, it reads "Tent operations (Steiner)".
  - The Mikado 921, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)
  - The Mikado (Swing) 905, Circa 1936-1939 (Box 100)